你们男生不懂的是
What you guys don't understand is,
接吻对女生的重要性
for us, kissing is as important as any part of it.
是嘛
Yeah, right!...
当真吗
Y'serious?
当然
Oh, yeah!
初吻可以让人明白一切
Everything you need to know is in that first kiss.
没错
Absolutely.
对我们而言
Yeah, I think for us,
接吻就像是暖场序幕
kissing is pretty much like an opening act, you know?
就像平克·弗洛伊德出场前
I mean it's like the stand-up comedian you have to sit through
你得耐着性子先看完暖场搞笑秀
before Pink Floyd comes out.
对  而且  我们并非
Yeah, and-and it's not that
讨厌搞笑表演  而是因为
we don't like the comedian, it's that-that...
只是我们买票又不是为了看搞笑秀
that's not why we bought the ticket.
问题在于演唱会结束后
The problem is, though, after the concert's over,
不论表演有多精采
no matter how great the show was,
你们女生总还想再重温暖场搞笑秀
you girls are always looking for the comedian again, you know?
我们在车中奋力杀出车阵
I mean, we're in the car, we're fighting traffic...basically
只是拼命让自己别睡着
just trying to stay awake.
是哦  给你个建议  让搞笑秀返场
Yeah, well, word of advice:Bring back the comedian.
否则下次你们只能坐在家里
Otherwise next time you're gonna find yourself
独自一人听唱片
sitting at home, listening to that album alone.
我们现在还在谈论性吗
...Are we still talking about sex?
不  挺好的  只是
No, it's good, it is good, it's just that- Mm-
她看起来是不是有点生气啊
doesn't she seem a little angry?
那是因为她有问题了
Well, she has issues.
真的吗
Does she?
她男人在外头拿着大棒敲昏别的女人
He's out banging other women over the head with a club,
而她却得在家
while she sits at home trying to
努力清除地毯上乳齿象的臭味
get the mastodon smell out of the carpet!
玛莎  他们是原始人
Marsha, these are cave people.
明白吗  他们关心的问题应该是
Okay? They have issues like
"嘿  冰川时代离我们越来越近了"
'Gee, that glacier's getting kind of close.'
-懂吗  -谈到问题  那不是你前妻吗
- See?  - Speaking of issues, isn't that your ex-wife?
我  不是
Me? No.
正是  卡罗尔  你好
Yes, it is. Carol! Hi!
好吧  是的
Okay.Yes.Yes,it is.
咱们到冰河世纪那边见好吗
How about I'll catch up with you in the Ice Age?
你的气色好极了  我
You look great. I, uh...
虽然我很不喜欢
I hate that.
抱歉  谢了  你看起来也不错
Sorry. thanks.You look good too.
在这儿任何直立的人
Ah, well, in here, anyone who...stands erect...
最近怎么样  还是
So what's new? Still, uh...
女同性恋
A lesbian?
世事难料嘛  那么
Well...you never know. How's, um...
家庭生活如何
how's the family?
玛蒂的疑心病还是很重  还有
Marty's still totally paranoid. Oh, and, uh-
卡罗尔  你来找我有什么事
Why- why are you here, Carol?
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
怀孕
Pregnant?!
她似乎不急着离开
she didn't leave in such a hurry after all
我猜这是《三人行》里
Oh, I think this is the episode of Three's Company where
他们有误会的那集
there's some kind of misunderstanding.
那我果真看过这一集
...Then I've already seen this one!
喝完没
Are you through with that?
真不好意思  我咽得太慢了
Yeah, sorry, the swallowing slowed me down.
这是谁的小纸团
Whose little ball of paper is this?!
应该是我的  我写给自己一张便条
Oh, uh, that would be mine. See, I wrote a note to myself,
后来觉得不需要  于是将它揉成纸团
and then I realised I didn't need it, so I balled it up and...
于是我现在不想活了
...now I wish I was dead.
那个枕头她已经拍过了
She's already fluffed that pillow...
莫妮卡  你已经拍过了枕头了  算了
Monica, you know,you've already fluffed that--but, it's fine!
抱歉各位
Look , I'm sorry, guys,
我只是不想给他们任何
I just don't wanna give them any more ammunition
借题发挥的机会
than they already have.
没错  众所周知父母对孩子的枕头
Yes, and we all know how cruel a parent can be
要求有多苛刻
about the flatness of a child's pillow.
莫妮卡
Monica? Hi!
莫妮卡  你吓到我了
Um, Monica, you're scaring me.
我是说  你现在一副慌张失措的样子
I mean, you're like, you're like all chaotic and twirly.
而且显得不是很好
And not-not in a good way.
对啊  放轻松
Yeah, calm down.
每次他们来时从没见
You don't see Ross getting all chaotic and
罗斯露出慌张的样子
twirly every time they come.
因为在我爸妈心目中  罗斯不可能犯错
That's because as far as my parents are concerned, Ross can do no wrong.
他是个王子
Y'see, he's the Prince.
显然  他们在我出生前有个大型仪式
Apparently they had some big ceremony before I was born.
什么
What?
丑裸男搞了个健腿器
Ugly Naked Guy got a thigh-master!
有人见我订婚戒指了吗
Has anybody seen my engagement ring?
有  挺漂亮的
Yeah, it's beautiful.
天哪  天哪  天哪  天哪
Oh God, Oh God, Oh God, Oh God, Oh God, Oh God, Oh God.
嘿  不要动它们
No, look, don't touch that!
还嫌我现在不够恐慌害怕吗
Oh, like I wasn't dreading tomorrow enough,
明天就得还他戒指了
having to give it back to him...
巴瑞  记得我不  我是那个身穿婚纱
'Hi Barry! Remember me? I'm the girl in the veil
当着你全家人的面让你颜面无存的女孩
who stomped on your heart in front of your entire family!'
天啊  如今我要去把戒指还给他
Oh God and now I'm gonna have to return the ring,
结果戒指没了  这是要逼死我啊
without the ring, which makes it so much harder...
别急  瑞秋  我们会找到的  对不
Easy Rach, we'll find it. Won't we!
是呀  没错
Oh! Yeah!
最后一次戴是在什么时候
Alright, when do you have it on last?
呆子  大概是在丢失之前咯
Doy! Probably right before she lost it!
这年头说"呆子"的人还真不多
You don't get a lot of 'doy' these days...
我今天早上还戴着呢
I know I had it this morning,
我记得当时我正在厨房
and I know I had it when I was in the kitchen with...
和黛娜一起吗
...Dinah?
别生气
Ohhhhh, don't be mad...
你不是吧
You didn't?
哦  对不起
Oh, I am sorry...
我就让你做了这么一件事情
I gave you one job!
不过这面条煮得还真直
Oh, but look how straight those noodles are!
莫妮卡  你明白的
Now, Monica, you know that's not
在千层面中找订婚戒指不是这个样子找的
how you look for an engagement ring in a lasagne...
我  办不到
I just...can't do it.
伙计们  动手吧
Boys? We're going in.
听语气不怎么开心啊
Wow. That is not a happy hi.
卡罗尔怀孕了
Carol's pregnant.
我找到了
Ooh! I found it!
什么  啥  怎么  什么
W-w-wh-...wha-...w-w-w-...
保持这个状态两小时
Yeah. Do that for another two hours,
你就会变成我现在这样了
you might be where I am right about now.
如此一来  就不用操心枕头的事了对吧
Kinda puts that whole pillow thing in perspective, huh, Mon?
那现在  你现在要怎么办
Well now, how-how do you fit into this whole thing?
卡罗尔说她和苏珊想让我也参与进来
Well, Carol says she and Susan want me to be involved,
但是我对此感觉很不自在  我不想掺和
but if I'm not comfortable with it, I don't have to be involved...
一切由我做决定
basically it's totally up to me.
她人好好  我真想念她
She is so great! I miss her.
她所谓的"参与"是什么意思
What does she mean by 'involved'?
我觉得  最大部分的工作你已经完成了
I mean presumably, the biggest part of your job is done.
总之  她们要我明天一起去
Anyway, they want me to go down to this-
做超声波检查
sonogram thing with them tomorrow.
你打算怎么做
So what are you gonna do?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
不管我怎么做  我都要当爸爸了
No matter what I do, though, I'm still gonna be a father.
面已经被搅乱了  不是吗
...Well, this is still ruined, right?
玛莎·卢德文的女儿会打电话给你
Oh, Martha Ludwin's daughter is gonna call you.
怎么会有咖哩味
Mmm! What's that curry taste?
那就是咖喱
Curry.
我觉得挺很好吃  真的
I- I think they're great! I, I really do.
你还记得卢德文一家人吗
Do you remember the Ludwins?
他家的大女儿挺喜欢你   对不
The big one had a thing for you, didn't she?
他们家的女儿都喜欢他
They all had a thing for him.
别这样  妈
Aw, Mom...
抱歉  她为何要打电话给我
I'm sorry, why is this girl going to call me?
她刚毕业  想找份烹饪的工作
Oh, she just graduated, and she wants to be something in cooking,
或是做饭啥的  我也不清楚
or food, or...I don't know.
总之  我告诉她你开了一家餐馆
Anyway, I told her you had a restaurant-
不  妈  我没开餐馆
No Mom, I don't have a restaurant,
我是在餐厅工作
I work in a restaurant.
他们不需要知道这个
Well, they don't have to know that...
罗斯  能过来帮我做意大利面吗
Ross, could you come and help me with the spaghetti, please?
-好  -我们要吃意大利面呀
- Yeah. - Oh, we're having spaghetti!
太简单了
That's...easy.
我知道这样要求过于自私
I know this is going to sound unbelievably selfish,
你能提一下孩子和女同性恋的事吗
but, were you planning on bringing up the whole baby/lesbian thing?
因为那样好歹能让我稍稍喘口气
Because I think it might take some of the heat off me.
瑞秋最近闯了那么大的祸
What that Rachel did to her life...
我们在俱乐部遇见她父母
We ran into her parents at the club,
他们很不开心
they were not playing very well.
我不会告诉你他们为婚礼耗费了多少钱
I'm not gonna tell you what they spent on that wedding...
但是四万块可是不少钱呢
but forty thousand dollars is a lot of money!
至少她曾拥有过把男人丢在教堂圣坛的机会
Well, at least she had the chance to leave a man at the altar...
这话算什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
没什么  表达一下亲情
Nothing! It's an expression.
不  才不是呢
No, it's not.
别听你妈的
Don't listen to your mother.
你独立自主  而且一直都这么独
You're independent, and you always have been!
就连你小时候也一样
Even when you were a kid...
那时你胖嘟嘟  一个朋友也没有
and you were chubby, and you had no friends,
你还是活得好好的
you were just fine!
你会独自待在自己房间里看书  玩拼图
And you would read alone in your room, and your puzzles...
而像罗斯这种人却注定要做人中之龙的
Look, there are people like Ross who need to shoot for the stars,
在博物馆工作  发表论文
with his museum, and his papers getting published.
其他人则安逸于现状
Other people are satisfied with staying where they are-
告诉你  这些人绝不会得癌症哦
I'm telling you, these are the people who never get cancer.
我曾读过一些女性也试图想拥有一切
...And I read about these women trying to have it all,
幸好咱家的小莫妮卡完全没有这种烦恼
and I thank God 'Our Little Harmonica' doesn't seem to have that problem.
罗斯  你最近怎么样
So, Ross, what's going on with you?
有啥情况吗
Any stories?
没有新闻八卦之类能和爸妈分享一下吗
No news, no little anecdotes to share with the folks?
好吧  好吧
Okay! Okay.
听着  我明白
Look, I, uh- I realise
你们一直想知道
you guys have been wondering
我和卡罗尔之间倒底出了什么事
what exactly happened between Carol and me, and,
事情是这样的
so, well, here's the deal.
卡罗尔是同性恋
Carol's a lesbian.
她现在和一个叫苏珊的女人住在一起
She's living with a woman named Susan.
她还怀了我的孩子
She's pregnant with my child,
并打算和苏珊共同抚养
and she and Susan are going to raise the baby.
这些你居然全都知道
And you knew about this?!
你的爸妈真的很不怎么样啊
Your folks are really that bad, huh?
你要知道他们特别专业
Well, y'know, these people are pros.
他们运筹帷幄
They know what they're doing,
慢慢部署  最后总能达到目的
they take their time, they get the job done.
常言道  父母是无法交换的
Boy, I know they say you can't change your parents,...
如果可以  我要你的父母
boy, if you could--I'd want yours.
我去尿尿
Must pee.
如果你是双胞胎  情况会更惨
Y'know, it's even worse when you're twins.
-你是双胞胎  -对  我们不往来
- You're twins? - Yeah. We don't speak.
她是那种精力充沛  事业心强的人
She's like this high-powered, driven career type.
她从事什么工作
What does she do?
服务生
She's a waitress.
好了各位  我得打扫了
All right, you guys, I kinda gotta clean up now.
钱德勒  你是独生子对吧
Chandler, you're an only child, right?
-你就没这些困扰  -没有
- You don't have any of this. - Well, no,
不过我有个想像中的朋友
although I did have an imaginary friend,
而我爸妈比较喜欢他
who...my parents actually preferred.
帮我关灯
The lights, please...
我刚在里面多久了
...How long was I in there?
我在做打扫
I'm just cleaning up.
那么  你  你需要帮忙吗
Do you...uh...do you need any help?
好呀  谢了
Uh...okay, sure! Thanks!
总之
Anyway...um...
明天要见巴瑞  紧张吗
So, you- uh- you nervous about Barry tomorrow?
有一点
Oh...a little...
很紧张
A lot.
有什么建议吗
So, got any advice?
作为一个刚刚被甩的人
Y'know, as someone who's recently been- dumped?
你应该避免用"甩"这个字眼
Well, you may wanna steer clear of the word'dumped'.
因为现在他很有可能正痛不欲生
Chances are he's gonna be this, this broken shell of a man, y'know,
而你也不该显得如此光艳照人
so you should try not to look too terrific,
我知道这一点很难做到
I know it'll be hard.
这样吧  我替你去一趟
Or, y'know, uh, hey! I'll go down there,
把巴瑞的戒指还给他
and I'll give Barry back his ring,
你陪卡罗尔和苏珊去做产科检查
and you can go with Carol and Susan to the OB/GYN...
你明天得见卡罗尔
Oh, you've got Carol tomorrow...
为什么会变得这么复杂啊
When did it get so complicated?
问倒我了
Got me.
-还记得我们在高中时吗  -记得
- Remember when we were in high school together? - Yeah.
那时我们难道不都认为自己会遇见一个人
I mean, didn't you think you were just gonna meet somone,
坠入爱河  然后厮守终生吗
fall in love- and that'd be it?
-罗斯  -对  没错
- Ross?  - Yes, yes!
没想到自己会沦落到这个地步
Oh! Man, I never thought I'd be here...
我也是
Me either...
抱歉  我迟到了  工作太忙
Sorry I'm late, I was stuck at work.
忙着处理巨型恐龙什么的
There was this big dinosaur...thing...anyway.
罗斯  记得苏珊吗
Ross, you remember Susan.
我怎能忘得了
How could I forget?
罗斯
Ross.
你好  苏珊  她的手好有力
Hello, Susan. Good shake. Good shake.
那么我们在等
So, uh, we're just waiting for...?
欧伯曼大夫
Dr. Oberman.
-欧伯曼大夫他  -是女的
- ...Dr. Oberman. Okay. And is he - She.
女的  当然了  那么她
She, of course, she- uh-
了解我们的特殊状况吧
familiar with our...special situation?
了解  而且她非常支持
Yes, and she's very supportive.
好  太好了
Okay, that's great.
不  我不用
No, I'm- Oh.
谢了
Thanks.
罗斯  那是用来打开我的子宫颈的
Ross? That opens my cervix.
巴瑞
Barry?
进来
Come in.
不打扰吧
Are you sure?
没问题  罗比得待在这儿好几个小时呢
Yeah! It's fine, it's fine. Robbie's gonna be here for hours.
最近好吗
So, how are you doing?
我还行  你的气色好极了
I'm- uh- I'm okay...You look great!
范瑞柏医生
Dr. Farber,
-杰森·格林斯坦吐了  -马上到
- Jason Greenstein's gagging. - Be right there.
我马上回来
Be back in a sec.
我甩的他
I dumped him.
接下来会怎么样
So, how's this all gonna work?
我是说  关于咱们仨
Y'know, with us?
比方说某些重大的决定
Y'know, when, like, important decisions have to be made?
举个例子
Give me a 'for instance'.
好吧  我也不知道  好吧好吧
Well, uh, uh, I don't know, okay, okay,
比方说  给孩子起名
how about with the, uh, with the baby's name?
-马龙  -马龙
- Marlon. - Marlon?
如果是男孩的话
If it's a boy,
如果是个女孩就叫米妮
Minnie if it's a girl.
跟米老鼠的女友同名
...As in Mouse?
和我奶奶同名
As in my grandmother.
不管怎样  听到米妮还是想到米老鼠
Still, you- you say Minnie, you hear Mouse.
对了  叫朱莉亚  怎么样
Um,how about, um...how about Julia?
朱莉亚
Julia...
我们决定用米妮
We agreed on Minnie.
很好  我俩还曾决定共度一生呢
Totally, um, uh, we agreed we'd spend the rest of our lives together.
世事难料  见招拆招
Things change, roll with the punches.
茱莉亚  可以作为备选吗
I believe Julia's on the table...?
真不好意思
Sorry about that.
对了  最近你过得如何
So. What have you been up to?
混得过去  我刚找到工作
Oh, not much. I-I got a job.
这太好了
Oh, that's great.
你怎么晒得这么黑
Why are- why are you so tanned?
我去阿鲁巴了
Oh, I, uh- I went to Aruba.
-你独自一人去度蜜月了  -不是
- Oh no. You went on our honeymoon alone? - No,
我是和  你也许会受伤
I went with, uh...Now, this may hurt.
-我吗  -不是
- Me?! - No!
我和明蒂去的
I went with Mindy.
明蒂  我的伴娘  明蒂吗
Mindy?! My maid of honour, Mindy?!
对  我们现在算是正式交往中
Yeah, well, uh, we're kind of a thing now.
哦  好吧  你去做植发了
Oh! Well...um, You've got plugs!
小心点  还没有固定得很好呢
Careful! They haven't quite taken yet.
你还配了隐形眼镜
And you've got lenses!
你不是讨厌将手指戳进眼里吗
But you hate sticking your finger in your eye!
为了她就不同了
Not for her.
听我说  我真的想谢谢你
Listen, I really wanted to thank you.
一个月前  我还想伤害你
See, about a month ago, I wanted to hurt you.
这辈子我都从未如此想去伤害某个人
More than I've ever wanted to hurt anyone in my life.
我可是个牙医呢
And I'm an orthodontist.
哇  对啊  你说得没错
Wow. You know, you were right?
我之前以为我们很幸福
I mean, I thought we were happy.
其实我们并不幸福
We weren't happy.
但和明蒂在一起  现在我很幸福
But with Mindy,now I'm happy.
-吐掉  -什么
- Spit. - What?
说我啦
Me.
算了
Anyway, um,
我想这个该还给你
I guess this belongs to you.
谢谢你将它送给我
And thank you for giving it to me.
好吧  也谢谢你送还给我
Well, thank you for giving it back.
喂
Hello!
拜托  海伦有什么不好
Oh, please! What's wrong with Helen?
海伦·盖勒
Helen Geller?
我不同意
I don't think so.
-她不会叫海伦·盖勒的  -谢谢
- It's not gonna be Helen Geller. - Thank you!
不  我是说她不姓盖勒
No, I mean it's not Geller.
难道她叫海伦·威利克
What, it's gonna be Helen Willick?
不  老实说
No, actually, um,
我们考虑用海伦·威利克·班奇
we talked about Helen Willick-Bunch.
等等  为何名字里有她的份
Well, wait a minute, wha- why is she in the title?
因为她也是我的孩子
It's my baby too.
真搞笑啊  我不记得你也贡献了精子
Oh, so funny, really? Um, I don't remember you making any sperm.
我们都知道那是个极大的挑战
Yeah, and we all know what a challenge that is!
够了  你们两个  别吵了
All right, you two, stop it!
不  功劳全让她抢了
No no no, she gets a credit,
拜托  我也是当事人好吗
hey, I'm in there too.
罗斯  你该不会想用
Ross. You're not actually suggesting
海伦·威利克·班奇·盖勒吧
Helen Willick-Bunch-Geller?
因为我觉得这样很像虐待儿童
Cause I think that borders on child abuse.
当然没有
Of course not,
我想用盖勒·威利克·班奇
I'm...suggesting Geller-Willick-Bunch.
不行  不行不行不行
Oh, no, nonononono,
你看出他的心思了吗
you see what he's doing?
他知道没人会叫全名的
He knows no-one's gonna say all those names,
这样大家只会叫她盖勒  他就此得逞
so they'll wind up calling her Geller, then he gets his way!
我得逞  你认为这样算得逞
My way?! You-you think this is my way?
相信我  我这辈子都没想到
Believe me, of all the ways
自己会沦落到这步田地
I ever imagined this moment in my life being,
这不是我想要的好吗
this is not my way- y'know what?
这太难了  我不行  我做不到
Uh, um, this is too hard. I'm not, I can't do-
有人在吗  今天如何  想呕吐吗
Knock knock! How are we today? Any nausea?
-一点点  -想吐  -有点儿吧
- A little. - Yeah. - Yeah.
好吧  我只是想问问准妈妈
Well, I was just wondering about the mother-to-be,
不过  谢谢你们这么配合
but...thanks for sharing.
躺好
Uh, lie back...
那个  我准备走了
You- uh- y'know what, I'm gonna go.
这件事太不寻常了
I don't- I don't think I can be involved
我觉得自己没办法参与进来
in this particular thing right now.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
看啊
Look at that.
我知道
I know.
怎么样  很神奇吧
Well? Isn't that amazing?
我们应该看到什么
What are we supposed to be seeing here?
我不知道  不过
I don't know, but...
我觉得它似乎马上要去攻击企业号
I think it's about to attack the Enterprise.
如果你们把头稍微向左偏
You know, if you tilt your head to the left,
两眼放空
and relax your eyes,
它的样子就像是一颗老土豆
it kind looks like an old potato.
那拜托不要那么看  行吗
Then don't do that, alright?
好
Okay!
莫妮卡  你认为呢
Monica. What do you think?
你是不是热泪盈眶呀
Wh- are you welling up?
不是
No.
你就是  你热泪盈眶
You are, you're welling up.
我没有
I'm not!
你就要成为姑姑了
You're gonna be an aunt.
闭嘴啦
Oh shut up!
喂  明蒂  喂  我是瑞秋
Hi, Mindy. Hi, it-it's Rachel.
我很好  我今天和巴瑞见面了
Yeah, I'm fine.I saw Barry today.
对  他告诉我了
Yeah, he told me.
不  没关系  真的  没事
No,i t's okay. Really, it's okay
我祝你们幸福快乐  真心祝福
I hope you two are very happy, I really do.
对了  明蒂  如果你们感情顺利
Oh, oh, and Mind, y'know, if-if everything works out,
最后能结婚生子的话
and you guys end up getting married and having kids-
那么
and everything-
希望你的孩子有他的发际线和你的糟鼻子
I just hope they have his old hairline and your old nose.
我知道这招很贱
Okay, I know it was a cheap shot,
但我感觉棒极了
but I feel so much better now.